<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CodeBuild on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/codebuild.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in CodeBuild on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/codebuild/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>c. Setup project in CodeBuild</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/04-codebuild.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/04-codebuild.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will create and setup a build project in AWS CodeBuild.
AWS CodeBuild is a fully managed continuous integration service that compiles source code, runs tests, and produces software packages that are ready to deploy.
With CodeBuild, you don’t need to provision, manage, and scale your own build servers
  In the AWS Management Console search bar, type and select CodeBuild. Double check that you are using CodeBuild in the same AWS Region that you have used in the previous steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>e. Auto execute pipeline</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/06-updatebuild.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/06-updatebuild.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, we will update the sample Dockerfile created earlier to automatically trigger the container build and update to Amazon ECR as part of the CodePipeline we created earlier.
We will modify the Dockerfile to run a Genomics workflow using Nextflow.
We will go over the Nextflow architecture and job execution/orchestration more in the next lab. For now, we will go ahead and update the repository and see how the CICD pipeline works for your build.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f. Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/07-conclusion.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Sep 2021 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/05-cicd-pipeline/07-conclusion.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations! You built a CI/CD pipeline uisng CodePipeline.
Your pipeline began with code in CodeCommit, built a Docker container and pushed the image to Elastic Container Registry (ECR) using CodeBuild.
In the next lab, you will learn about container orchestration and how to deploy your container using AWS Batch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
