<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>initialize on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/initialize.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in initialize on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/initialize/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>b. Set up AWS ParallelCluster foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/03-initialize-pc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/03-initialize-pc.html</guid>
      <description>Typically, to configure AWS ParallelCluster, you use the interactive command pcluster configure to provide the information, such as the AWS Region, VPC, Subnet, and Amazon EC2 Instance Type. For this workshop, you will create a custom configuration file to include the HPC specific options for this lab.
In this section, you will set up the foundation (for example network, scheduler, &amp;hellip;) required to build the ParallelCluster config file in the next section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c. Create a Cluster Config</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/04-configure-pc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/04-configure-pc.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you installed AWS ParallelCluster and set up the foundation, you can create a configuration file to build a simple HPC system. This file is generated in your home directory.
Generate the cluster with the following settings:
 Head-node and compute nodes: c5.xlarge instances. You can change the instance type if you like, but you may run into EC2 limits that may prevent you from creating instances or create too many instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c. Run nextflow container</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/04-launch-nextflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/04-launch-nextflow.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will run a basic pipeline for quantification of genomic features from short read data implemented with Nextflow. Nextflow enables scalable and reproducible scientific workflows using software containers.
1. Create a new container image with nextflow Let&amp;rsquo;s begning by creating a new version of the container image.
Change the Dockerfile with the nextflow container
cd $CONTAINER_WORKDIR cat &amp;gt; Dockerfile &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF FROM nextflow/rnaseq-nf ENV DEBIAN_FRONTEND=noninteractive RUN apt-get --allow-releaseinfo-change update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update -y &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get install -y git python3-pip curl jq RUN curl -s https://get.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
