<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>packer on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/packer.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in packer on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/packer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>c. Set up Batch Resources</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/03-setup-batch-ce-jq.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/03-setup-batch-ce-jq.html</guid>
      <description>In this step, you set up an AWS Batch Compute Environment and Job Queue via infrastructure as code using AWS Cloudformation.
Compute environments can be seen as computational clusters. They can consist of one or several instance kinds or just the number of cores you want in the environment. For more information on the compute environments, see Compute Environments.
The Job Queue is where you submit your jobs. These jobs are dispatched to the compute environment(s) of your choosing by order of priority.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>f. Run a Single Job</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/06-run-job.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/06-run-job.html</guid>
      <description>In this step, you launch a job using the AWS CLI. (Note that you could also use the AWS Management Console or the AWS SDK to submit jobs, but this workshop does not cover those options.)
Run the following command on Cloud9 terminal to run a single job..
aws batch submit-job --job-name nextflow-job --job-queue nextflow-jq --job-definition nextflow-demo --region $AWS_REGION  If the job does not run, double-check that the job queue name and job definition are correct.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
