<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud9 Step by Step on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud9 Step by Step on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:05:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prerequisites</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/02-requirement_notes.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/02-requirement_notes.html</guid>
      <description>The following prerequisites are required for the HPC workshops:
 A computer with an internet connection running Microsoft Windows, Mac OS X, or Linux. An internet browser such as Chrome, Firefox, Safari, Opera, or Edge. Familiarity with common Linux commands.  If you have any questions when running this workshop, speak with your group coordinator or contact AWS HPC.
This workshop includes multiple code samples that you can copy and paste using the button shown below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a. Event: Accessing Your Lab Account</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/03-access-aws.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:50:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/03-access-aws.html</guid>
      <description>Accounts are only accessible for the duration of the event. To continue using AWS after the event, create an AWS Account.
 Do not hesitate to ask questions at isc22tutorial@amazon.com if you need any help.
Step 1 Sandbox were available on May 29th 2022 for the duration of the tutorial. If you would like to run through the labs at a later stage on your own, with your company or institution, please contact us at isc22tutorial@amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>b. Post Event: Access AWS (Skip)</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/03-aws-console-login.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/03-aws-console-login.html</guid>
      <description>Skip this step if you are doing the labs during the ISC22 event.
Depending on your workshop, you may access the AWS Management Console through direct sign-in (here) or as directed by your trainer. To sign in, enter your AWS Account ID or alias, IAM user name, and password that was provided to you for this lab.
After you sign in, take a few minutes to explore the navigation components of the AWS Management Console.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>b. Create a Cloud9 Environment</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/04-start_cloud9.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/04-start_cloud9.html</guid>
      <description>AWS Cloud9 is a cloud-based integrated development environment (IDE) that lets you write, run, and debug your code with just a browser. This workshop uses Cloud9 to introduce you to the AWS Command Line Interface (AWS CLI) without the need to install any software on your laptop.
AWS Cloud9 contains a collection of tools that let you code, build, run, test, debug, and release software in the cloud using your internet browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c. Work with the AWS CLI</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/05-start-aws-cli.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/05-start-aws-cli.html</guid>
      <description>Your AWS Cloud9 Environment should be ready. Now, you can become familiar with the environment, learn about the AWS CLI, and then create an Amazon S3 bucket with the AWS CLI. This S3 bucket is used in the next module.
AWS Cloud9 IDE Layout The AWS Cloud9 IDE is similar to a traditional IDE you can find on virtually any system. It comprises the following components:
 file browser, listing the files located on your instances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>d. Attach Role to Cloud9 Instance</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/06-iam-role.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/06-iam-role.html</guid>
      <description>In this step, you will create an IAM role with Administrator access and configure Cloud9 to use the IAM role for the rest of this lab.
AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) enables you to manage access to AWS services and resources securely. Using IAM, you can create and manage AWS users and groups, and use permissions to allow and deny their access to AWS resources.
By configuring Cloud9 to use the IAM role, you will allow your Cloud9 instance to access any services of your AWS account.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summary</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/99-summary.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/07-aws-getting-started/99-summary.html</guid>
      <description>During this workshop, you learned how to build a basic infrastructure in the AWS Cloud. Specifically, you learned how to:
 Access and use the AWS Management Console Create an AWS Cloud9 Environment Attach an IAM role to an AWS Cloud9 Instance  In the next section, you learn how to build an HPC cluster using AWS ParallelCluster. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
