<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nextflow on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/nextflow.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in nextflow on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/nextflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>d. Set up a Job Definition</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/04-setup-batch-job-definition.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/04-setup-batch-job-definition.html</guid>
      <description>In this step, you set up a template used for your jobs, known as a job definition. A job definition is not required, but a good practice to use so that you can version how your jobs are launched. For more information about job definitions, see Job Definitions.
Run the following commands on your Cloud9 terminal
 Copy the Cloudformation template which will be used to create the AWS Batch Job Definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>g. Monitor your jobs</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/07-monitor-job.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/07-monitor-job.html</guid>
      <description>In this step, you will monitor your submitted jobs on the Batch console
  Go to the Batch console and click on the Dashboard on the left hand side   The Dashboard gives you an overview of your Batch environment (i.e. Compute Environment, Job Queues and status of the submitted Jobs). The Job queue overview shows the different Job States that a batch job runs through during its execution cycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>h. Cleanup</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/08-cleanup.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/06-batch-automation/08-cleanup.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations! You have completed the container orchestration lab and learnt how to deploy your containers using AWS Batch.
In Lab 3 you build and pushed your container to ECR in an automated way using CICD pipeline via CodeCommit and CodeBuild. In Lab 4 you deployed the same container using Batch.
In this section, you will clean all the resources that you created in Lab 3 and Lab 4.
Clean Up After you complete the workshop, clean up your environment by following these steps:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
