<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>create on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/create.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in create on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/tags/create/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>e. Build an HPC Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/06-launch-pc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/06-launch-pc.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you create a cluster based on the specifications defined in the configuration file. To create a cluster, you use the command pcluster create-cluster.
In your AWS Cloud9 terminal, run the following to create a cluster. Make sure that the configuration file path is correct.
pcluster create-cluster --region ${AWS_REGION} --cluster-name hpc-cluster-lab --cluster-configuration my-cluster-config.yaml The pcluster create-cluster command might output a few warnings, the cluster creation will progress.
TeamRole:~/environment $ source env_vars TeamRole:~/environment $ pcluster create-cluster --region ${AWS_REGION} --cluster-name hpc-cluster-lab --cluster-configuration my-cluster-config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>h. Connect to the Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/09-connect-cluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/09-connect-cluster.html</guid>
      <description>The cluster we created on the previous page takes about ~10 mins to create. While you&amp;rsquo;re waiting grab a ☕️.
Once the cluster goes into CREATE COMPLETE, we can connect to the head node in one of the following three ways, either through the shell, via the DCV, or via SSH:
SHELL is ideal for quick terminal access to the head node.
DCV is a full graphical remote desktop that allows you to run GUI applications on the head node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>i. Get to know your Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/10-run-commands.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/10-run-commands.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you are connected to the head node, familiarize yourself with the cluster structure by running the following set of commands.
SLURM SLURM from SchedMD is one of the batch schedulers that you can use in AWS ParallelCluster. For an overview of the SLURM commands, see the SLURM Quick Start User Guide.
  List existing partitions and nodes per partition. You should see two nodes if your run this command after creating your cluster, and zero nodes if running it 10 minutes after creation (default cooldown period for AWS ParallelCluster, you don&amp;rsquo;t pay for what you don&amp;rsquo;t use).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>l. CONUS 12-km Model</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/11-conus-12km.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/11-conus-12km.html</guid>
      <description>The steps here can also be executed on any cluster running SLURM. There may be some variations depending on your configuration.
 In this step, you run the WRF CONUS 12km test case job to introduce you to the mechanisms of AWS ParallelCluster.
Preparatory Steps Make sure that you are logged into the AWS ParallelCluster head node through the AWS Cloud9 terminal.
 Download CONUS 12KM Input data used for simulating the Weather Research and Forecasting (WRF) model are 12-km CONUS input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>m. Run WRF</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/12-run-wrf.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/12-run-wrf.html</guid>
      <description>Submit your First Job Submitted jobs are immediately processed if the job is in the queue and a sufficient number of compute nodes exist.
If there are not enough compute nodes to satisfy the computational requirements of the job, such as the number of cores, AWS ParallelCluster creates new instances to satisfy the requirements of the jobs sitting in the queue. However, note that you determined the minimum and maximum number of nodes when you created the cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>n. Visualize Results</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/13-visualize-results.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/13-visualize-results.html</guid>
      <description>In this next section, we&amp;rsquo;re going to visualize the results of the job we just ran using NCL. NCL will be pre-installed on your Cluster.
  Connect to the Head node via DCV, following instructions from part f. Connect to the Cluster
  In a terminal navigate to the WRF run directory.
  cd /shared/conus_12km The provided ncl_scripts/surface.ncl script will generate two plots of surface fields at valid time 2019-11-27 00:00.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>o. Summary</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/14-exit-cluster.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2022 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/03-hpc-aws-parallelcluster-workshop/14-exit-cluster.html</guid>
      <description>Congratulations, you have deployed a HPC Cluster on AWS !
In this lab, you have:
 Configured your HPC Cluster Deployed a HPC Cluster in the cloud. Run a tighly couple application: WRF on the CONUS 12KM test case.  In the next lab, you will learn how to build a Docker container image and how to run a container on the HPC cluster in the cloud.
You can learn more about AWS ParallelCluster by visiting the documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
