<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Container on AWS ParallelCluster on AWS HPC Workshops</title>
    <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Container on AWS ParallelCluster on AWS HPC Workshops</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2019 09:05:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a. Update your cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/02-update-pc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/02-update-pc.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will update the configuration of the HPC cluster you created in Lab I to:
 Create a post-install script to install Docker and Singularity. Provide access to the container registry, Amazon Elastic Container Registry (ECR). Create a new queue that will be used to run the containerized workload. Update the configuration of the HPC Cluster.  The following commands must be executed on the AWS Cloud9 environment created at the beginning of the tutorial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>b. Create container repository</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/03-create-repository.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/03-create-repository.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will create a container repository on Amazon ECR and create a Docker container image.
Preliminary In the AWS Cloud9 terminal, connect to the HPC Cluster
pcluster ssh hpc-cluster-lab -i ~/.ssh/$SSH_KEY_NAME -r $AWS_REGION Since the HPC Cluster existed prior to post-install script, you will need to manually install Docker and Singularity on the head node of the HPC Cluster.
# Install Docker sudo amazon-linux-extras install -y docker sudo usermod -a -G docker ec2-user sudo systemctl start docker sudo systemctl enable docker # Install Singularity sudo yum install -y singularity Exit the HPC cluster</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>c. Run nextflow container</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/04-launch-nextflow.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/04-launch-nextflow.html</guid>
      <description>In this section, you will run a basic pipeline for quantification of genomic features from short read data implemented with Nextflow. Nextflow enables scalable and reproducible scientific workflows using software containers.
1. Create a new container image with nextflow Let&amp;rsquo;s begning by creating a new version of the container image.
Change the Dockerfile with the nextflow container
cd $CONTAINER_WORKDIR cat &amp;gt; Dockerfile &amp;lt;&amp;lt; EOF FROM nextflow/rnaseq-nf ENV DEBIAN_FRONTEND=noninteractive RUN apt-get --allow-releaseinfo-change update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get update -y &amp;amp;&amp;amp; apt-get install -y git python3-pip curl jq RUN curl -s https://get.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>d. Terminate Your Cluster</title>
      <link>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/06-delete-pc.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 10:46:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.hpcworkshops.com/04-container-parallelcluster/06-delete-pc.html</guid>
      <description>Now that you are done with your HPC cluster, you can delete it.
Let&amp;rsquo;s exit the cluster to go back to your AWS Cloud9 terminal.
exit On AWS Cloud9 terminal, let&amp;rsquo;s delete the cluster with the following command
pcluster delete hpc-cluster-lab -r $AWS_REGION The cluster and all its resources will be deleted by CloudFormation. You can check the status in the CloudFormation Dashboard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
